Guide to the Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Materials removed from Printed Items, 1903-80, n.d.; Series VII; 0.42; (1 box)
  - WORKS BY OTHERS
    - Photocopy of holograph of Hardy's poem "Cry of the Homeless", 1915 Aug (Box 32, Folder 938)
      Removed from: Wharton, Edith. The Book of the Homeless (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1916)
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 939)
      Removed from: Whistler, James McNeill. The Gentle Art of Making Enemies... (London: William Heinemann, 1890)
    - Newspaper clippings (Photos of Hardy), 1927 Aug 7 (Box 32, Folder 940)
      Removed from: Unidentified volume
- Oversize, 1881-1978; 9; (5 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from Series I, III, IV, V, and VI, arranged in Series order.
  - Writings of Thomas Hardy
    - The Dynasts
      - The Dynasts, "A German Dissertation on the Dynasts " by A. W. G. Randall, review, The Saturday Westminster Gazette, 1920 Jul 31 (Box 26, Folder 822)
    - The Mayor of Casterbridge
      - Drawings by Robert Barnes, photocopies, n.d.
    - "No Bell-Ringing"
      - Printed version, The Sphere, photocopy, 1925 Nov 23
    - "Our Exploits at West Poley"
      - Printed version, The Household, photocopy, 1892-93 (Box 26, Folder 823)
      - Response to inquiry ["La France est-elle en décadence?"]
        - Printed version, L'Européen, photocopy, 1904 Mar 26
    - Tess of the D'Urbervilles
      - Review by P. and Q., The World, photocopy, 1892 Jan 13
    - "Thomas Hardy's Graphic Description of Maiden Castle"
      - Printed version, The Detroit Post, photocopy, 1885 Mar 15 (Box 26, Folder 824)
  - Thomas Hardy Association Material
    - Photographs
      - Hardy, Florence - Portrait, [ca. 1920] (Box 27, Folder 825)
      - Hardy, Thomas - Portrait, signed, [ca. 1910] (Box 27, Folder 826)
    - Scrapbooks
      - Dugdale, Constance - Dugdale-Hardy wedding and married life, 1914-57 (Box 27, Folder 827)
      - Dugdale, Constance - Thomas Hardy death and burial, 1928 Jan (Box 27, Folder 828)
      - Marion Terry and "Far From the Madding Crowd" production, 1882-87 (Box 28, Folder 829)
        [includes letter from Marion Terry to Emma Hardy, 1883]
    - Time Books
      - Time book for "The Dynasts" - Volume 2: Miss Lillah McCarthy and Mr. Granville Barker, 1914 Jul 1 (Box 28, Folder 830)
  - Thomas Hardy Research Material
    - Articles
      - Cassell's Weekly tribute issue, including "Thomas Hardy in his 84th Year" by Henry W. Nevinson; "A Hardy Dialogue" by E. Hallam Moorhouse; and "Lionel Johnson on the Wessex Novels", 1923 Jun 20 (Box 28, Folder 831)
      - "Mr. Hardy's Poems" The Saturday Westminster Gazette, 1919 Dec 6 (Box 28, Folder 832)
      - Shorter, Clement King, "A Literary Letter: The American Critics and the English," The Sphere, 1925 Sep 19 (Box 28, Folder 833)
    - Clippings
      - Architecture, 1928, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 834)
      - Archives, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 835)
      - Biography, 1920-78, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 836)
      - Centenary, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 837)
      - Death and Burial, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 838)
      - Dorset Villages, Homes, etc., 1898-1949 (Box 29, Folder 839)
      - Drawings by Hardy, 1957-63, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 840)
      - Exhibitions - Yale, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 841)
      - General Critical Notices, 1881-1929 (Box 29, Folder 842)
      - General Critical Notices, 1930-62 (Box 29, Folder 843)
      - Hardye's School, Dorchester, 1961 Feb 25 (Box 29, Folder 844)
      - Reviews - Poems, 1899-51, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 845)
      - Thomas Hardy Festival, 1968 Jul (Box 29, Folder 846)
    - Correspondence
      - Purdy, Richard to his parents, 1929-38 (Box 31, Folder 857)
        Notebook of transcripts of letters sent during Purdy's trips to England to do research on Hardy. Given by Michael Millgate.
    - Ephemera
      - Biographical sketch of Thomas Hardy (with illustrations), ca. 1895 (Box 30, Folder 847)
      - Family Trees - Dugdale, Gifford, Hand, and Hardy
      - Parody of "The Squire," Funny Folks, photocopy, 1882 May 27
      - Print, "Tess" [Thomas Hardy] by Spy, from Vanity Fair, 1892 Jun 14
    - Printed Material
      - Exhibition - Yale, Posters, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 848)
  - Sydney C. Cockerell Papers
    - Other Materials
      - Clippings about Thomas Hardy
        - Centenary, 1940 Jun 6 (Box 30, Folder 849)
        - Death and Burial, 1928-40 (Box 30, Folder 850)
        - General Critical Notices, 1922-42 (Box 30, Folder 851)
        - Hardy bust, 1926 Feb 10 (Box 30, Folder 852)
        - Hardy using wireless, 1923 Nov 29 (Box 30, Folder 853)
        - Henniker, Florence, 1897 Jul 29 (Box 30, Folder 854)
        - Tess, 1923-29 (Box 30, Folder 855)
  - Non-Hardy Material
    - CORRESPONDENCE
      - Browning, Robert
        - Letter to Dr. E. Waring, 1887 Nov 10 (Box 30, Folder 856)
        - [with clipping from Pall Mall Gazette, 1887 Nov 9, annotated by Dr. Waring]